tsa.gov 2019-06-23

# Privacy Policy | Transportation Security Administration

TSA is committed to protecting privacy and securing personal information made available when accessing this website. This page provides information on what is collected on this website, how the information is used and retained. As a general rule, TSA does not collect personal information when you are browsing tsa.gov. Personal information is collected only when it is voluntarily provided to us. You do not have to provide personal information in order to visit this website. The information you provide is shared with another government agency if your inquiry relates to that agency, or is otherwise required by law.

TSA will collect and protect your information consistent with the principles of the [Privacy Act of 1974](http://www.justice.gov/opcl/privacy-act-1974), [E-Government Act of 2002](https://it.ojp.gov/default.aspx?area=privacy&page=1287) and [Federal Records Act](http://www.archives.gov/records-mgmt/laws/). Learn about the [privacy impact assessments](http://www.dhs.gov/privacy-documents-transportation-security-administration-tsa), also known as PIA.

## Information Collected Automatically

When you access this website, there is some basic information that is automatically collected and temporarily stored. The information collected is used for improvements within the website and for technical and operating system enhancements. The information collected does not identify you personally.

The information collected includes:

  * The Internet domain (for example, 'xcompany.com' if you use a private Internet access account or 'yourschool.edu' if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web) from which you access this website.
  * The type of browser (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer, Chrome) and operating system (e.g., Windows, Mac OS, Unix) used to access this site.
  * The date and time you access this site.
  * The pages you visit.
  * If you linked to this website from another website, the address of that website.

TSA uses the information collected to count the number and type of visitors to the different pages on this site and to help us make the site more useful to visitors.

## How TSA Uses Cookies

The Office of Management and Budget Memo [M-10-22, Guidance for Online Use of Web Measurement and Customization Technologies](https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/sites/default/files/omb/assets/memoranda_2010/m10-22.pdf) allows Federal agencies to use session and persistent cookies.

When you visit any website, its server may generate a piece of text known as a "cookie" to place on your computer. Placing cookie text allows websites to “remember” visitors’ preferences, surfing patterns and behavior while they are connected.

The cookie makes it easier for you to use the dynamic features of webpages. Cookies from tsa.gov webpages only collect information about your browser’s visit to the site; they do not collect any personal information about you.

There are two types of cookies, single session (temporary), and multi-session (persistent). Session cookies last only as long as your web browser is open. Once you close your browser, the cookie disappears. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer for longer periods.

Session Cookies: TSA uses session cookies for technical purposes such as to enable better navigation through our site. These cookies let our server know that you are continuing a visit to our site. The OMB Memo 10-22 Guidance defines our use of session cookies as "Usage Tier 1-Single Session.” The policy says, "This tier encompasses any use of single session Web measurement and customization technologies."

Persistent Cookies: TSA uses persistent cookies to differentiate between new and returning visitors to our site. Persistent cookies remain on your computer between visits to tsa.gov for six months. TSA also uses persistent cookies to block repeated invitations to take our customer satisfaction survey. The persistent cookies that block repeated survey invitations expire in 90 days. The OMB Memo 10-22 Guidance defines our use of persistent cookies as "Usage Tier 2-Multi-session without personally identifiable information (PII).” The policy says, "This tier encompasses any use of multi-session web measurement and customization technologies when no PII is collected."

3rd party software, modules, or add-ins being leveraged on TSA website may or may not use persistent cookies or similar technology; however, no data collected in this manner is accessible, viewable, or retained by the federal government.

If you do not wish to have session or persistent cookies stored on your machine, you can opt out or disable cookies in your browser. You will still have access to all information and resources on the TSA website. However, turning off cookies may affect the functioning of some of the TSA website. Be aware that disabling cookies in your browser will affect cookie usage at all other websites you visit as well.

TSA currently uses Google Analytics to perform web measurements and analytics. Google Analytics sets a single session cookie and three persistent cookies that expire up to two years after they are set.

## Email

You may choose to provide personal information in an email. TSA uses the information to improve customer service or to respond to a question. Sometimes TSA may forward your email to other government employees who may be better able to assist. Please do not include sensitive personally identifiable information (e.g. social security numbers, passport or alien registration numbers) in an email.

## Third Party Websites

This website has links to third-party sites, including other federal agencies, and private organizations or commercial sites. When you visit a link to another website from tsa.gov, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new website. TSA uses third-party commercial websites such as Twitter and YouTube to interact with the public on issues related to TSA functions.

TSA does not endorse, support or otherwise promote any private or commercial entity that may be reached through links on this website.

## Disclaimer and Liability Notice

This website is monitored to ensure proper operation and to verify the functionality of applicable security features. Anyone using this website consents to such monitoring. Unauthorized attempts to modify any information stored on this website, to defeat or circumvent security features, or to utilize this system for other than its intended purposes may be unlawful and result in criminal prosecution.

## Restriction of Liability

TSA makes no claims, promises or guarantees about the accuracy, completeness or adequacy of the contents of this website and expressly disclaims liability for errors and omissions in the contents of this website. No warranty of any kind, implied, expressed or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement of third party rights, title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and freedom from computer virus, is given with respect to the contents of this website or its hyperlinks to other Internet resources. Reference in this website to any specific commercial products, processes, or services, or the use of any trade, firm or corporation name is for the information and convenience of the public, and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation or favoring by TSA.

## Ownership

Information presented on the website is considered public information and may be distributed or copied. TSA shall have the unlimited right to use for any purpose, free of any change, all information submitted via this site except those submissions made under separate legal contract. TSA shall be free to use, for any purpose, any ideas, concepts or techniques contained in information provided to TSA through this site.

## Social Media Comment Policy

TSA encourages the public to share thoughts as they relate to the topics being discussed on official social media accounts.

TSA uses the official social media accounts to engage with and provide information to the public. TSA cannot guarantee a response to all comments and questions due to volume. If you have a travel related issue or question that requires immediate assistance, you can contact TSA.

Comments and responses posted to any official TSA social media accounts are subject to the usage policies of the respective websites.

The views expressed in visitor comments reflect those of the comment’s author and do not necessarily reflect the official views of TSA or the federal government.

TSA does not guarantee or warrant that any information posted by individuals is correct, and disclaims any liability for any loss or damage resulting from reliance on any such information. TSA may not be able to verify, does not warrant or guarantee, and assumes no liability for anything posted by any other person. TSA does not endorse, support or otherwise promote any private or commercial entity or the information, products or services contained that may be reached through links posted by others in comments.

TSA does not moderate comments prior to posting, but reserves the right to delete comments that contain:

  * Threats to individuals or groups.
  * Obscene, harassing or defamatory language.
  * Discrimination targeting individuals or groups.
  * Unsolicited bulk messages and posts that contain harmful links, also known as "spam."
  * Promotion of services or products (not including non-commercial links that are relevant to the topic).
  * Suggestions or encouragement of illegal activity.
  * Personal or sensitive information (phone numbers, email or postal addresses).

Repeated violations of this policy may result in the user being removed from the TSA social media channels.

Complaints about abusive comments and removal requests should be sent to [socialmedia@tsa.dhs.gov](mailto:socialmedia@tsa.dhs.gov).

Do not use TSA social media accounts to report criminal activity. If you have information for law enforcement, please contact your local police agency.

TSA social media accounts may not be used for the submission of any claim, demand, informal or formal complaint, or any other form of legal and/or administrative notice or process, or for the exhaustion of any legal and/or administrative remedy.

Thank you for taking the time to read this comment policy. We encourage your participation in our discussion and look forward to an active exchange of ideas.

If you are a reporter, please contact the press office at [(571) 227-2829](tel:+15712272829) or [tsamedia@tsa.dhs.gov](mailto:tsamedia@tsa.dhs.gov).

TSA reserves the right to modify this policy at any time.
